Alejandro Beltran

Email: alebelcor@gmail.com & GitHub: github.com/alebelcor & LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/alebelcor &

I'm a Software Engineer from Mexico focused on Web Front End with 10+ years of experience with a specialty and passion for UI, Web performance, and Web accessibility.

EXPERIENCE

• ConsumerTrack, Inc. 🗗

via Nearsoft

Front End Engineer (Remote)

Apr 2020 - Present

Technologies: JavaScript, React, Redux, Next.js, HTML, CSS, Sass (SCSS), Twig, Bootstrap, Node.js, npm, Jest, React Testing Library, Babel, ESLint, Husky, Webpack, CircleCI, jQuery, PostCSS, Visual Studio Code, Git

- o Focused on Front End Engineering for ImportantScore.com & and GOFreeCredit.com & that offer consumers fast and easy online access to their credit score and credit monitoring services via the three national credit bureaus: Experian, Equifax, and TransUnion
- Led Web performance efforts to improve our performance score and Web Vitals, as part of our team mission, which
 has resulted in a 68% (mobile) and 17% (desktop) increase in performance score points for GOFreeCredit.com.
 And a 43% (mobile) and 17% (desktop) increase for ImportantScore.com.
- o Implemented several other performances optimizations: next-gen image formats, image optimizations, visible text during webfont load, reduced requests size, eliminated dead dependencies, added resource hints, asynchronous/lazy loading of render-blocking resources.
- Implemented A/B tests and experiments to determine the most successful variation to integrate and help increase revenue, gross profit, GPM, and various other C2C rates.
- Implemented automation of data management for CCPA compliance and to reduce the manual work of over 600 inquiries per month for "Delete My Data", "See My Data" and "Do Not Sell My Data" requests.

• American Tours International, LLC □

via Nearsoft

Software Engineer (Remote)

Nov 2019 - Mar 2020

Technologies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Sass (SCSS), React, React Bootstrap, React Router, Reselect, Jest, React Testing Library, Create React App, PropTypes, Node.js, Express, ESLint, Prettier, Husky, Yarn, date-fns, Visual Studio Code, SVN with git-svn

- Led an engineering team of two in charge of implementing a modern, fast, and aesthetic re-imagining of ATI's internal administration tool used by travel agents for payment and transaction review, and processing.
- Designed the shapes, payload/content, and headers of the HTTP API requests and responses.
- Implemented pure client-side user session management.
- o Implemented auto-refresh mechanism of JWT token.
- Implemented data tables with pagination, sorting, expandable rows with sub-component rendering.
- o Implemented custom column filters for tables, e.g. text, date (with date picker widget), number range, and select.
- Implemented test suite with 90% code coverage for actions/components/hooks/reducers/selectors/services/utils.
- Implemented maintainable and customizable CSS architecture using Sass, Bootstrap (with overrides), and BEM.
- Implemented mock back end API server using Express for faster and better DX.
- $\circ\,$ Integrated code linting and auto-formatting for JS/JSX files as part of test suite, and VS Code.

• Switchfly, LLC □

via Nearsoft

Software Engineer (Remote)

Feb 2014 - Aug 2019

Technologies: JavaScript, Java, HTML, CSS, Sass (SCSS), Ember.js, Handlebars.js, Git, Gulp, JSHint, Karma, Mocha, Chai, npm, jQuery, Selenium, Jenkins, Ant, Maven, FreeMarker, ColdFusion, PostgreSQL, IntelliJ IDEA

- Implemented interstitial/loading page for better SEO and accessibility.
- Implemented custom responsive navigation with auto-collapsing items based on viewport.
- Increased performance by implementing preloading of the next page assets.
- Increased performance by reducing/consolidating-and compression-of Ajax HTTP requests/responses.
- ∘ Integrated PAYBACK® ♂ and Masterpass™ ♂ payments into checkout process.
- Added automated end-to-end test cases for all new features in Selenium Java.

- Added base, and custom analytics for clients, for data-based product and UI/UX decision making.
- Refactored codebase to meet AA level of the WCAG 2.0 accessibility standard.
- Peer-reviewed other people's code as "Subject Matter Expect" of the shopping experience.

• Evolve Media, LLC

via Intugo

Senior Software Engineer (Remote)

Jul 2013 – Feb 2014

Software Engineer (Remote)

Jul 2012 - Jul 2013

Technologies: JavaScript, PHP, WordPress, HTML, CSS with Sass (SCSS), Compass, and Susy, jQuery, SVN with git-svn, Jenkins, Ant, npm, Grunt, JSHint, Capistrano

- Worked as Software Engineer focused on Front End Engineering for multiple heavily trafficked and highly ranked websites targeting, among other things: women, fashion, sports, gaming and entertainment.
- о Examples: the FashionSpot ${\tt C}$, Momtastic ${\tt C}$, SuperHero Hype ${\tt C}$

• OptumInsight ♂

via Nearsoft

Application Development Engineer (Remote)

Jan 2009 - Jun 2012

Technologies: Java, Java EE, Servlets, JavaScript, LotusScript, Formula Language, Lotus Notes, Lotus Domino, Tomcat, HTML, CSS, XML, XPath, XSLT, SVN, CVS, RCS, Maven, Ant, Make, Jenkins

• Worked as Application Development Engineer extending and maintaining their EMR Lite system, related services and applications.

EDUCATION

SKILLS

• Institute of Technology of Hermosillo

Hermosillo, MX

Bachelor of Computer Systems Engineering

Dec 2008

CERTIFICATIONS

• Responsive Web Design

freeCodeCamp

• JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures

freeCodeCamp

• Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate ID: TLSZSQSVHG-MMSTYQSQ-RPFDLKRHJT Scrum Foundation

- Software Engineering: Agile Software Development, Software Release Cycle, Unit Testing, Integration Testing, End-to-end Testing, Continuous Integration, Software Security, Static Code Analysis
- Front End (Web): HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Web Performance, Web Accessibility, React, React Hooks, Redux, CSS-in-JS, Sass (SCSS), Bootstrap
- Tools: Node.js, npm, Yarn, ESLint, Prettier, Jest, React Testing Library, Git, Visual Studio Code